There are six ways to get the same customer
to pay you more money.
First is obviously to increase price.
So if fulfillment stays the same,
then every dollar of price increase
drops straight to the bottom line, which is good.
Number two is you can decrease costs.
So you decrease the cost of whatever it takes you
to fulfill your product or service.
Number three is you increase purchase frequency.
Getting somebody to buy your product or service more times.
Number four is upselling.
Getting somebody to buy a bigger or better
or premium version of whatever they just bought.
Number five is cross-sell.
Getting someone to buy an additional
or complimentary product or service
in addition to their original purchase.
Number six is a down sell.
So you sell a smaller, less expensive,
less premium version of your main thing.
This is a small slice of the taxes
that we use to grow our portfolio company
that generates over $250 million per year.